Amiri Baraka papers 6909686
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Amiri Baraka papers
1945-2015
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014
6909686
MS#1482
219.5 linear feet 219.5 linear feet
The Amiri Baraka Papers contains correspondence, writings, and the personal, political activism and teaching materials related to Amiri Baraka's career as a poet, writer, editor, activist, and teacher in the New York City Beat, Downtown, and Black Arts literary scenes from the 1960s through the 2000s. Included are manuscripts from Baraka's numerous books of poetry, non-fiction, fiction, plays, editorial work, and screenplays. The collection also features organizational and documentary materials relating to Baraka's university teaching and Newark, NJ-based black radical activism, as well as audio/visual material, photographs, and printed material collected and created by Baraka.
Conditions Governing Access
225 audio recordings digitized as part of the Coordinated Project for Preservation Reformatting of Audio Reel to Reel Tapes to Digital Format, funded by the New York State Program for the Conservation and Preservation of Library Research Materials, 2013-2014
Restrictions on Access
This collection is located on site.
Restrictions on Access
All original copies of audio / moving image media are closed until reformatting in 2020. Some unique time-based media items have been reformatted and will be available onsite via links in the container list. Commercial materials are not routinely digitized. Email rbml@columbia.edu for more information.
Restrictions on Access
Material containing information about Baraka's students or that have personal information or grades about students are restricted for 75 years from the month of creation.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the correspondence, writings, teaching, activist, and personal materials, audio/visual and photographic material relating to Amiri Baraka's career as a poet, writer, teacher, and activist, as well as items pertaining to his personal life. Correspondence ranges from 1945 to 2007, and comprises a wide variety of correspondents, including business and literary contacts, friends, fans, and family.
Scope and Content
Among the writings are notes, drafts, correspondence, and publication material pertaining to many of Baraka's poetry, fiction, plays and screenplays, non-fiction, and editorial projects primarily after 1973, both published and un-published. Also included are drafts and research material for the poem "Somebody Blew Up America," as well as drafts of essays, correspondence, petitions of support, and clippings about the subsequent Poet Laureate controversy. Finally, there is a large body of writings—fiction, non-fiction, poetry, and plays—by others.
Scope and Content
Other series included herein are those containing materials relevant to Baraka's teaching at various colleges and universities, including SUNY-Stony Brook, Rutgers, Columbia, and Naropa. A separate series holds the organizational papers, correspondence, reports, and research materials surrounding Baraka's political organizing and activism, particularly his work with various black nationalist, Pan-African, and international socialist/Maoist groups. A separate series is comprised of by materials related to Kimako's Blues People, the club, performance venue, and salon founded by Baraka and his wife Amina in Newark. A series of personal items contains many notebooks and loose notes produced by Baraka, material relating to his family, and financial, legal, and medical documents, as well as Baraka's FBI files.
Scope and Content
This collection also encompasses a large body of audio/visual material produced by Baraka and others, including audio cassettes, film reels, DVDs, CDs, and visual art in a variety of mediums. Much of the A/V material relates to Baraka's work with black nationalist and Pan-African political groups. A final series contains printed material, including flyers about Baraka's readings, appearances, and performances; political and cultural events organized by Baraka and others; clippings about Baraka; and many literary journals, little magazines, poetry chapbooks, and political newspapers containing work by Baraka.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
2007.2008.M070: Source of acquisition--Imamu Amiri Baraka. Method of acquisition--Purchase; Date of acquisition--2007.
Biographical Note
Poet, writer, activist, and teacher Amiri Baraka (born Everett LeRoi Jones) was born October 7, 1934 to Coyt Leverette and Anna Lois Jones in Newark, NJ, a postal supervisor and a social worker, respectively. In 1952 Baraka entered Howard University, leaving before graduating. He subsequently studied at both Columbia University and the New School for Social Research in New York City, also without taking a degree.
Biographical Note
In 1954, Baraka entered the United States Air Force as a gunner, stationed in Puerto Rico. Reaching the rank of sergeant, Baraka served until 1957 when he was dishonorably discharged for the possession of prohibited political literature.
Biographical Note
Settling in Greenwich Village, Baraka became active in the Downtown literary, arts, and music scenes, marrying Hettie Cohen in 1958, with whom he would have two children, Kellie Jones (b. 1959) and Lisa Jones (b.1961). Together, Baraka and Jones founded and co-edited the seminal avant-garde literary magazine Yugen in 1958 and, later, Totem Press, which published early works by Allen Ginsberg, Jack Kerouac, and other Beat and Downtown experimental writers. At the same time, Baraka worked as editor and critic for the literary and art journal Kulchur. In 1961, Baraka's first collection of poetry, Preface to a Twenty Volume Suicide Note… was published by Totem/Corinth Press.
Biographical Note
From 1961 to 1963, Baraka co-edited, with Diane Di Prima, the little magazine The Floating Bear. Baraka and Di Prima later founded the New York Poets Theatre, alongside choreographers Fred Herko and James Waring, and actor Alan S. Marlowe. With Di Prima, Baraka would go on to have a daughter, Dominique Di Prima, born in 1962.
Biographical Note
In 1960, Baraka took a seminal trip to Cuba as part of a Fair Play for Cuba Committee delegation, which provided the basis for his essay "Cuba Libre." Upon return, he co-authored the statement of support for Fidel Castro, Declaration of Conscience with Margaret Randall, Marc Schleifer, Elaine de Kooning, Diane Di Prima, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, and Norman Mailer, which was published in the Monthly Review.
Biographical Note
The mid-Sixties saw Baraka becoming more prominent in the literary and arts scenes, with the 1963 publication of the major study of blues and African American music, Blues People: Negro Music in White America, and his editorship of The Moderns: An Anthology of New Writing in America. In 1964, the production of his play Dutchman at Cherry Lane Theatre in New York brought him to the attention of the dramatic arts world, and the play later won an Obie for "best off-Broadway play," and was turned into a film by Anthony Harvey in 1966.
Biographical Note
Following the assassination of Malcolm X in 1965, Baraka left Hettie Jones and their children and moved uptown to Harlem, declaring himself a black cultural nationalist. Here he founded and directed the Black Arts Repertory Theatre-School and published his first and only novel The System of Dante's Hell, before moving back to the city of his birth, Newark, NJ.
Biographical Note
In 1966 Baraka married Sylvia Robinson, and the following year they adopted the Bantuized Muslim names of Imamu ("spiritual leader," subsequently dropped) Ameer ("Prince," later Amiri) Baraka ("blessed") and Amina Baraka. Baraka also began teaching at San Francisco State University where he began an association with cultural nationalist leader Ron Karenga.
Biographical Note
This same year, in the midst of the Newark riots, Baraka was arrested and injured by police on charges of unlawful weapons possession and resisting arrest. Initially convicted of a misdemeanor, the charges were reversed on appeal. During this period, Baraka's political organizing became more prominent, and his poetry became more overtly political as well, particularly his volume Black Magic and the seminal Black Arts Movement anthology Black Fire, co-edited with Larry Neal. In 1970, Baraka helped mayoral candidate Kenneth Gibson become the first African American mayor of Newark. He also worked as an organizer and participant in the Congress of African Peoples which met in Atlanta and, in 1972, the National Black Political Convention in Gary, Indiana.
Biographical Note
Another major shift in Baraka's political beliefs and aesthetics occurred in 1974, when he rejected black nationalism and declared his conversion to "Marxism-Leninism-Mao Tse-tung Thought", or Third World Marxism, in the essay "Toward Ideological Clarity," published in Black World. The following year saw the publication of his first Marxist poetry collection, Hard Facts. Though Baraka's politics would continue to develop, he remained a Third World Marxist for the rest of his life and career.
Biographical Note
In 1979, Baraka became a lecturer in the Africana Studies Department at SUNY-Stony Brook. That same year, Baraka was arrested during an altercation with Amina and sentenced to 48 weekends in a Harlem halfway house, during which he wrote The Autobiography of LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, first published in 1984. In this same year, Baraka and Amina found Kimako's Blues People, a multimedia arts space, located in their basement in Newark.
Biographical Note
In 1990 Baraka became active in the campaign to achieve major curricular reform in the Newark public schools. He was, in the same year, denied tenure at Rutgers University, which became a major rallying point for anti-racism campus activism. During this period he worked on several major biographical projects, co-writing both the autobiography of Quincy Jones and the unfinished and unpublished Max Roach autobiography, with whom he had previously collaborated on The Life and Life of Bumpy Johnson, a musical drama.
Biographical Note
In 2002, New Jersey governor Jim McGreevey named Baraka the state's Poet Laureate. Soon after, he became embroiled in a controversy over his September 11th poem "Somebody Blew Up America," which critics accused of being anti-American and ant-Semitic. Unable to oust Baraka from the position, Governor McGreevey and the State Legislature ultimately abolished the post of Poet Laureate. Baraka was subsequently named Poet Laureate of the Newark Public School System.
Biographical Note
Over the course of his career, Baraka received fellowships from the Guggenheim Foundation and the National Endowment for the Arts, the PEN/Faulkner Award, a Rockefeller Foundation Award for Drama, the Langston Hughes Award from The City College of New York, and a lifetime achievement award from the Before Columbus Foundation.
Biographical Note
Amiri Baraka died on January 9, 2014, in Newark, New Jersey, after being periodically hospitalized for one month prior to his death. After struggling for a long period with diabetes, Baraka died from complications after a recent surgery. His funeral was held at Newark Symphony on January 18, 2014
American literature -- African American authors; Beats (Persons); Bohemianism; Civil rights; Civil rights and socialism; Counterculture; Little magazines; Poetry -- Publishing; Poetry -- Social aspects; African American poets; Politics; Politics and literature; Political plays; Politics in art; Race relations in literature; Radicalism; Radicalism in art; Teaching; Sound recordings; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Newark (N.J.); Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014
- Series I: Correspondence, 1945-2007
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains personal and business correspondence to and from Baraka from the 1960s through the 2000s. The materials are primarily organized alphabetically by correspondent, with additional caches of correspondence from Baraka's immediate family and children, as well as Allen Ginsberg, Nina Simone, and photocopies of his correspondence with the poet Ed Dorn. The material includes holographs, typescript, and computer-printed letters, as well a large body of printed emails. Additional correspondence can be found in other series, relevant to that subject.
  - General, 1970-2007
    - 1970s 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - 2000s 2000-2007, (11 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 7-17)
    - Undated, (6 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Alphabetical, 1945-2007
    - A, 1972-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1980s 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (5 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-9)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
      - General, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - B, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (4 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (5 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 19-23)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - C, 1968-2007
      - 1968-1970s 1968-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1980s 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (4 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 7-10)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (4 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
      - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - D, 1972-2007
      - 1970s 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - 1980s 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
      - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - E, 1972-2007
      - 1970s 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1980s 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - General, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - F, 1975-2007
      - 1970s-1980s 1975-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
      - General, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - G, 1973-2007
      - 1970s 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (4 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (4 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
      - General, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - H, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
      - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - I, 1983-2007
      - 1980s 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - J, 1972-2007
      - 1970s 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 18-20)
      - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - K, 1972-2007
      - 1970s 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (4 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
      - General, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - L, 1975-2007
      - 1970s 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
      - General, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - M, 1971-2006
      - 1970s 1971-1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (5 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-25)
      - 2000s 1990-1999, (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
      - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - N, 1984-2007
      - 1980s 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
      - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - O, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - 1980s 1982-1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - P, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
      - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Q, 1983-2003
      - 1980s 1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - 1990s 1990-1995 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - 2000s 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - R, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - 1980s 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
      - General, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - S, 1968-2007
      - 1960s-1970s 1968-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - 1980s 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (5 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 11-15)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-18)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - T, 1971-2007
      - 1970s 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 1980s 1980-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
      - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - U, 1980-2005
      - 1980s 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 1990s 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - 2000s 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - V, 1979-2003
      - 1970s 1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - 1980s 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 1990s 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - 2000s 2003 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - W, 1945-2007
      - 1940s-1970s 1945-1977 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - 1980s 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 21-22)
      - 1990s 1990-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 23-25)
      - 2000s 2000-2007, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - General, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - X, 1986-2001
      - 1980s 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1990s 1991-1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 2000s 2001 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - General (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Y, 1978-2007
      - 1970s 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 1980s 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 1990s 1991-1998 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - General, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Z, 1982-2007
      - 1980s 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cards, 1996-2007
    - Holiday, Birthday, and Thank You, 1996-2007; (5 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-19)
    - Shani Sympathy, 2003; (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
    - Shani Sympathy, 2003; (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dorn, Ed (Photocopies), 1959-2005; (3 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
  - Family, 1985-2007
    - General, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Baraka, Ahi, 1998-2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Baraka, Amiri, Jr., undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Baraka, Obalaji, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Baraka, Ras, 1986-2006 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Baraka, Shani, 1985-2004 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - DiPrima, Dominique, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jones, Kellie, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Jones, Lisa and Zoe, 1989-2007 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "German Tours", 1980-2005 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1984-1997 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Howard University Homecoming, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "John Coltrane,", 1971-1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Literary Assignments", 1994-1997; (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - Simone, Nina, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Speaking and Reading Engagements", 1984-1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - SUNY Stonybrook, 1983-1995 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
- Series II: Writings, 1958-2009
  - Subseries 1: Non-Fiction, 1966-2009
    This series contains the manuscript drafts and publication materials relating to Amiri Baraka's published and unpublished body of non-fiction essays, memoirs, and books. Highlights include the holographs, typescripts, and proofs of various editions, and relevant correspondence, notes, and contracts of The Autobiography of LeRoi Jones,Home: Social Essays, The Creation of the New Ark, Digging,The Essence of Reparations, Eulogies, and The Music. In addition, this series contains the drafts, submissions, notes, and correspondence relating to Baraka's anthology efforts, including the seminal Black Fire, Black Fire 2, and Confirmation, and the mixed media poetry and political newsletter RAZOR. This series contains a large group of material, including drafts, notes, interview transcripts, and research materials, relating to the unpublished Max Roach autobiography. Also included are the drafts, notes, and research materials of Baraka's essays and books about Jesse Jackson and John Coltrane. Finally, Drafts of interviews with Baraka and Baraka's own published liner notes can also be found in the series. This series is organized largely alphabetically by title, and chronologically by date, while larger caches of material have been given their own folders.
    - General, 1966-2007
      - Alphabetical By Title, 1966-2007
        - A, 1985-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - B, 1969-2005; (3 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
        - C, 1970-2006 (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - D, 1970-2005 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - E, 1969-1997 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - F, 1984-2006 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - G, 1983-2006 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - H, 1970-2003 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        - I, 1976-2002 (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - J, 1989-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
        - K, 1992-2002 (Box 12, Folder 13)
        - L, 1982-2004 (Box 12, Folder 14)
        - M, 1970-2000 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        - N, 1967-2007 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - O, 1981-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - P, 1970-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
        - R, 1981-2005 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - S, 1980-2005; (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
        - T, 1976-1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - U, 1998-2003 (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - V, 1981-2004 (Box 13, Folder 10)
        - W, 1966-2006 (Box 13, Folder 11)
        - Y, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
        - Z, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Untitled By Date, 1970s-2000s
        - 1970s 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14)
        - 1980s 1982-1988 (Box 13, Folder 15)
        - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 13, Folder 16)
        - 2000s 2002-2006 (Box 13, Folder 17)
        - Untitled, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
        - Untitled, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - "Abbie Hoffman Memorial", 1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Activist and Political, 1979-2003 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - "An Afro-American Family Call for Unity & Struggle,", 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Afro-America, 'White America' & The Million Man March,", 1997 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - "Agit-Prop Committee", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - "Aides (sic): Whose Epidemic", undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Albert Ayler, 2002-2003 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - "Anti-Imperialist Cultural Union", 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - "Anti-Semitism: A Personal Understanding", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 9)